全速前进!
Man the yards! Quick on all canvas!
小伙子们，姑娘们，围过来
Gather round, lads and lasses. Gather round.
被绑架上船，准备“深红海盗”号的最后一次巡航…很久很久以前，在遥远的加勒比海。
You've been shanghaied aboard for the last cruise of the Crimson Pirate... a long, long time ago in the far, far Caribbean.
记住，在海盗船里，在海盗水域里，在海盗世界里……不要问问题。只相信你所看到的。
Remember, in a pirate ship, in pirate waters, in a pirate world... ask no questions. Believe only what you see.
不。相信你所看到的一半。
No. Believe half of what you see.
操纵绞盘! 起锚!
Man the capstan! Up anchor!
快走，你们这些笨蛋!
Move, you lubbers!
右舷有船!
Ship to starboard!
注意!
Attention!
一艘坏血病船，阁下。
A scurvy ship, Your Excellency.
你可以通过四肢的位置来判断。坏血病害死了所有船员。
You can tell by the position of the limbs. Scurvy's killed the whole crew.
漂亮的小船，船长Rodríguez。
A trim little ship, Captain Rodríguez.
我们把她拖走。她会带来一大笔钱。
We'll take her in tow. She'll bring a tidy sum.
派一名军官和两名船员上船，天黑前把船拖过来。
Put an officer and two men aboard her, and have her in tow by nightfall.
是,是,先生。
Aye, aye, sir.
只有恶魔才能从死亡之船上来——啊。
- Only evil can come from a death ship. - Aye.
Sanctus，他们中的一个碰了我!
Sanctus, one of them touched me!
他们俩后来怎么样了?
What happened to those two?
跟我来。
Follow me.
我诚挚的歉意。
My humble apologies.
无聊?
Bored?
要是有什么东西能打破这次航行的单调就好了。
If only there was something to break the monotony of this voyage.
请的手在空中。
Hands aloft, please.
你们是瓦洛船长和他的卑鄙船员的俘虏。
You're the prisoners of Captain Vallo and his scurvy crew.
你可能太自信了，瓦洛船长。
You may be overconfident, Captain Vallo.
这艘船上有两百名海军陆战队员。
Two hundred of the King's marines are aboard this vessel.
只有20个海盗。这让我的胜算稍微大一些。
And only 20 pirates. That puts the odds slightly in my favor.
-最好交出船。-我只是个过客。
- Better surrender the ship. - I am merely a passenger.
-他是谁?——Gruda男爵。
- Who is he? - Baron Gruda.
觐见陛下的特使。
Special envoy to His Majesty.
这是我的荣幸。
Well, this is a pleasure.
-你绞死了我的大部分朋友。-因为你杀了我的大部分人。
- You hanged most of my friends. - For murdering most of mine.
看来你现在只有199名陆战队员，男爵。
Seems you have only 199 marines now, Baron.
198. 最好说服上尉投降。
198. Better persuade the Captain to surrender.
船长不是那种…197.
The Captain is not the type to... 197.
不过，如果你允许我跟他谈谈……
However, if you'll permit me to speak to him...
奥乔，给队长传个话。
Ojo, pass the word for the Captain.
打倒船长!
Bring down the Captain!
叫舰长下来!
Send down the Captain!
保存船长!
Save the Captain!
叫舰长下来!
Send down the Captain!
你找船长了吗，先生?
Did you ask for the Captain, sir?
看不见你。向他致意，请他进来。
Aye. Pay him my compliments and show him in.
聚集,小伙子。聚集。
Gather round, lads. Gather round.
我们很幸运。
We're in luck.
大家很快就会大开杀身之祸了。
All hands will soon be digging into a fat divvy.
我们即将迎来史上最盛大最精彩的海盗时代。
We're heading for the biggest and the best pirate days ever.
这是一个大概的数字。
And here's the rich tally in round numbers.
“火枪:3000。
"Muskets: 3,000.
“粉桶:1500。
"Powder kegs: 1,500.
“步枪发射了65000发。
"Rounds of musket shot: 65,000.
-“炮弹……“——请原谅我打断你……可是你什么时候才能挖到金子呢?
- "Rounds of cannon shot... " - Begging thy pardon for interrupting... but when will thee get into the gold?
听着,伙伴,倾听。
Listen, fellows, listen.
这片海域有许多岛屿正冒着反抗国王的浪潮……只是因为没有枪才没发火。
There are islands in these waters steaming with rebellion against the King... and kept from boiling over only for lack of guns.
在这些岛屿上，枪比金子还值钱。
Islands where guns are worth more than gold.
-不仅仅是钻石。——军火走私?
- More than diamonds. - Gunrunning?
但那不是海盗，船长。这是生意。
But that's not piracy, Skipper. That's business.
-意思是在岸上工作。-我们的浮力很差。
- That means working ashore. - We're doing poorly enough afloat.
如果我们要尝试这种新手法，那就好好干。
If we're going to try this new caper, let's make it a good one.
这批货能从任何有价值的叛军那里带来五万金币弗罗林。
This cargo will bring 50,000 gold florin from any rebels worth the name.
- 50000弗罗林?-拍得不错。
- 50,000 florin? - That's a pretty good take.
让我们投票表决吧。所有赞成……如果你不介意我打断你的话，船长……我想在投票前好好想想。
Let's put it to the vote. All those in favor... If you'll forgive my interrupting, Skipper... I'd like to think before I vote.
与此同时，我们还有普通的海盗生意要解决。
Meantime, we got regular pirate business to settle.
我们得到了木板，罪犯和判决。
We got the plank, the culprit, and the verdict.
我们只需要审判和执行一个判决。
All we need's a trial and execution of a sentence.
他是有罪的!
He's guilty!
审判到此为止。现在执行。
So much for the trial. Now for execution.
来吧。杀了我，你们这些傻瓜。
Come on. Kill me, you fools.
国王的海军会搜遍七大洋直到你们每个人都被绞死。
The King's Navy will scour the Seven Seas till every one of you is hung high and dry.
-跟他一起到木板上去!——停住!
- To the plank with him! - Avast!
他不会走木板路的。
There'll be no plank-walking for him.
原谅我的迟钝，船长……但你是在要求我们放过这只可爱的蟾蜍吗?
Forgive my slow-wittedness, Skipper... but are thee asking us to spare this sweet-smelling toad?
请大人原谅。
Begging Thy Excellency's pardon.
你们队长比你们所有人加起来都聪明。
Your captain's got more brains than all of you put together.
你肯定是想拿我来勒索赎金。
No doubt you intend to hold me for ransom.
不，我的羽毛漂亮的朋友。我给你自由。
No, my fine-feathered friend. I'm setting you free.
我说，如果猴子对我们没有好处，我们就享受我们的乐趣。
I say, if there's no profit in the monkey we'll have our pleasure.
我说他是有好处的。活着。
I say there is profit in him. Alive.
-多少利润?-现在听我说完。
- How much profit? - Now hear me out.
我说叛军给我五万弗罗林买枪…而在这里，由特别委员会负责的，就是国王的首席反叛军捕手。
I said 50,000 gold florin from the rebels for the guns... and here, by special commission, is the King's chief rebel-catcher.
所以为什么不从他和他的国王那里再得到5万美元呢?告诉他们我们把枪都卖给了哪个叛军。
So why not another 50,000 from him and his king... for telling them which rebels we sell all the guns to.
呃,男爵?
Eh, Baron?
好主意，上尉。我的祝贺。
A brilliant scheme, Captain. My congratulations.
你的祝贺。
Thy congratulations.
如果你是为了它，它就不是为了海盗的利益。
If thou art for it, it is not for the good of pirates.
好吗?先生们,这是宏伟的。
Good? Gentlemen, it's magnificent.
我要去眼镜蛇岛抓一个叫El Libre的人，粉碎他的叛乱。
I'm bound for the Island of Cobra to catch a man, El Libre, and smash his rebellion.
如果你把枪带到那里，把他从洞里引到我手里……我再给你加5万。
If you'll take the guns there, lure him out of his hole and into my hands... I'll raise the purse another 50,000.
这就是，伙计们，大概的数字:15万弗罗林。
There it is, lads, in round figures: 150,000 florin.
现在你觉得怎么样，Humble Bellows先生?
What do you say now, Mr. Humble Bellows?
你卑微的仆人会相信的……当你卑微的仆人看见它。
Thy humble servant will believe it... when thy humble servant sees it.
我想我们达成协议了，上尉。
I take it we have a deal, Captain.
船长，这次换船，真不舒服。
This change of ship, Captain, most uncomfortable.
我的人不会转移货物的。太像诚实的工作了。
My men won't transfer cargo. Too much like honest work.
瓦洛船长，你的人只给我留了头帆和上帆。
Captain Vallo, your men have only left me headsail and topsail.
它们足以让你迟早找到眼镜蛇。
They're enough to get you to Cobra sooner or later.
我的船比这艘驳船快。
My ship is faster than this barge.
我不希望你在我把El Libre准备好交付之前进港……或者在我背后开一枪。
I don't want you making port before I've got El Libre ready for delivery... or putting a shot in my backside.
我希望El Libre不像你这么小心，上尉。
I hope El Libre is not as careful as you are, Captain.
摆脱舵!
Cast off helm!
摆脱严厉!
Cast off stern!
-贝洛斯先生，开船!-是，是，先生!
- Mr. Bellows, make sail! - Aye, aye, sir!
把车拉上来，全速前进。
Haul up, full and by.
也没有”和“东方。我们正前往眼镜蛇岛。
Nor' nor' east. We're heading for the Isle of Cobra.
来吧，你们这些笨蛋，快走!
Come on, you lubbers, move!
你们听，你们听!
Hear ye, hear ye!
国王的船现在抛锚了……在眼镜蛇港，格鲁达男爵在船上。
The King's vessel is now at anchor... in the port of Cobra with Baron Gruda aboard.
任何示威都将被视为叛国罪。
Any demonstration will be regarded as high treason.
人们看起来很安静，不是吗?
The people seem very quiet, don't they?
我不认为他们打算示威反对格鲁达男爵。
I don't think they intend to demonstrate against Baron Gruda after all.
-显然不是，州长-太遗憾了。
- Apparently not, Governor. - What a pity.
我们的军队可以像砍麦子一样砍倒他们。
Our troops could've cut them down like wheat.
我们就不能照一般原则拍几部吗?
Couldn't we shoot a few on general principles?
也许能打动男爵。
Might impress the Baron.
他可能觉得你只是在找麻烦。
He might feel you are merely provoking trouble.
最令人恼火。向格鲁达男爵敬礼。
Most exasperating. Fire the salute to Baron Gruda.
注意!
Attention!
你一声令下，我就给那些背后捅刀子的人来一枪。
Give the word and I'll dose those backstabbers with a broadside.
他们没朝我们开火，你个脑残猿。
They're not firing at us, you powder-brained ape.
他们要给我们放15响礼炮。我们要高举格鲁达的旗帜。
They're giving us a 15-gun salute. We're flying the flag of Gruda.
Slimey，把旗子拿出来，把我给你的信息拿出来。
Slimey, bring out the flags and run up that message I gave you.
Slimey，代我向州长问好。
And, Slimey, give the Governor my compliments.
深红色的海盗的吗?
The Crimson Pirate's?
不，你这个牡蛎头，格鲁达男爵。
No, you oyster-head, Baron Gruda's.
贝洛斯先生，把这些半桅杆的猴子留在甲板下面。
Mr. Bellows, keep the rest of these half-masted monkeys below deck.
是,是,队长。
Aye, aye, Skipper.
小伙子们，请密切注意。我今晚会和El Libre一起回来。
Keep a sharp lookout, lads. I'll be back with El Libre tonight.
我们走吧,处。
Let's go, Ojo.
有一个好海盗，像卖鱼的一样卖他的货物。
There goes a good pirate, to sell his wares like a fish peddler.
当然，这不是对船长的不尊重。
Meaning no disrespect to the Skipper, of course.
有人悬赏我们的人头…也像活靶子一样在国王陛下的港口挖了个洞
Us with a price on our heads... holed, too, in one of His Majesty's ports like sitting ducks.
但如果船长能让我们再渡过难关，我们就成了有金蛋的鸭子。
But if the Skipper pulls us through again, we'd be the ducks with the golden eggs.
你想的是鹅，请原谅我的纠正，毒药保罗。
You're thinking of geese, if you'll pardon the correction, Poison Paul.
大雁在徒劳地追逐。
Geese on a wild-goose chase.
他们说什么，约瑟夫?
What do they say, Joseph?
他们把瘟疫带上船了，他们在隔离自己…直到受害者被杀死或治愈。
They've got the plague onboard, and they're quarantining themselves... until the victims are killed or cured.
我们必须向格鲁达男爵表示深切的哀悼。
We must signal my profound condolences to Baron Gruda.
-很好，州长。-也许这样最好，约瑟夫
- Very well, Governor. - Maybe it's all for the best, Joseph.
El Libre的追随者们可能会出手给我一个机会让男爵刮目相看 叫我的马车
El Libre's followers may yet show their hands... and give me a chance to impress the Baron. Order my carriage.
驱散人群。换掉守卫，在街上加倍巡逻。
Disperse the crowd. Change the guard, and double your patrols in the street.
来吧，我的小妹妹。
Come on, my popsy-wopsy-wopsies.
瘟疫,是吗?愿它带走所有的人。男爵Gruda第一。
Plague, is it? May it take all of them. Baron Gruda first.
是啊，就算瘟疫没来，我们也得去。
Aye, and if the plague don't, we will.
-你是谁?-像你们这样单纯的渔民。
- Who are you? - Simple fisher folk like yourselves.
请他给我一杯麦芽酒，说句友好的话，再给我个机会跟国王决斗。
Put in for a tankard of ale, a friendly word, and a chance to fight the King.
为什么选择我们?
Why choose us?
你看起来和说话都像个斗士。
You look and talk like a fighter.
同类相知。
It takes one to know one.
你可能已经盯上我们了。也许不是。
You may have us marked, all right. Maybe not.
但我们还没有给你做标记。
But we haven't marked you yet.
-我们不会问任何问题——我们。
- We're asking no questions. - We are.
我对El Libre的了解已经足够了。
What I've heard about El Libre is good enough for me.
告诉我们怎么联系他。
Tell us how to contact him.
像他这样的人，要是船上有两个强壮的小伙子，一定会很高兴的。
A man like him would be pleased to have two more strong-armed lads aboard.
他们不太相信别人，对吧?
Not very trusting souls, are they?
我想我们得证明我们对El Libre的高度尊重。
I guess we'll have to prove our high regard for El Libre.
奥乔，你说出了我想说的话。
Ojo, you took the words right out of my mouth.
和国王的人打架。我们走吧。
A brawl with the King's men. Let's go.
左,右。离开了。马克的时间!
Left, right. Left. Mark time!
右转。
Right turn.
停止!
Halt!
齐步走! 前进! 停下! 转弯！
Quick march! Forward! Halt! Turn!
右转!
Right wheel!
前进!
March!
停!
Halt!
举枪致敬!
Present arms!
共和国万岁!
Long live the republic!
叛军!抓住他们!
Rebels! Get them!
El Libre 万岁!
Long live El Libre!
之后他们!
After them!
他们在那!
There they are!
别让他们跑了!
Don't let them get away!
男人!来吧!
Men! Come on!
来吧!快去那个角落。
Come on! Quick, in that corner.
他们走了!
There they go!
快点，到后面去。
Hurry up. In back.
这里!
This way!
去做吧。
Go ahead.
皮尔斯画布上。
Pierce the canvas.
火!
Fire!
准备好了吗?火!
Ready? Fire!
把它捡起来!提升起来!来吧。提升起来!火!
Pick it up! Lift it up! Come on. Lift it up! Fire!
把我们带走。
Take us away.
他们得到了!
They're getting away!
门闩酒窖!块小巷!
Latch the cellars! Block the alley!
看出来。士兵。
Look out. Soldiers.
只是一分钟。
Just a minute.
搜索的地方。
Search the place.
-这臭味能把猪赶跑。-确实如此。
- The stink would drive away a pig. - Which it did.
看那扇门。
Watch that door.
你救了我们，孩子，你救了我们。
You've saved us, lad, you've saved us.
我们是自己人。
We're among our own kind.
叛军。
Rebels.
如果你是El Libre我也不会惊讶。
Wouldn't surprise me if you were El Libre himself.
-你看起来像天生的领袖。-我叫巴勃罗·墨菲
- You look like a born leader of men. - The name's Pablo Murphy.
我从我父亲那里学到了很多爱尔兰语，所以我一听就知道什么是巧言。
And I got enough Irish from me father to know blarney when I hear it.
我们早就因为你窥探间谍而割了你的喉咙了……只因为你对那些士兵所做的。
We'd have slit your throats for snooping spies by now... only for what you did to them soldiers.
-他们是谁?——谁知道呢?
- Who are they? - Who knows?
这个不能说话，这个不能保持安静。
This one can't talk and this one can't keep quiet.
好吧，我们有话直说。我是瓦洛船长，愿为您效劳。
All right, let's get to the point. I'm Captain Vallo at your service.
这位是奥乔中尉。
And this is Lieutenant Ojo.
法洛?海盗?
Vallo? The pirate?
深红色的海盗?
The Crimson Pirate?
没错，我的好妈妈，我们为El Libre做了笔交易…一船火药和步枪
That's right, sweet mother, with a bargain for El Libre... a shipload of powder shot and musketry.
-格鲁达男爵的船。-格鲁达男爵的船?
- Baron Gruda's ship. - Baron Gruda's ship?
看不见你。格鲁达男爵自己的30枪手。
Aye. Baron Gruda's own 30-gunner.
我们轻而易举地就拿下了她，好渔夫。
We took her as easy as you'd take a mackerel, fine fishermen.
更容易。因为我们用的是死诱饵。
Easier. For we used dead bait.
你杀了巴伦·格鲁达?
You killed Baron Gruda?
如果我这么做了，你就不需要我卖给你的枪了。
If I did that you wouldn't need the guns I want to sell you.
我是海盗，不是杀狗人。
I'm a pirate, not a dog killer.
但我喜欢你们。我喜欢你的风格。
But I like you lads. I like your style.
所以，聚集在一起，看看这个:
So gather round and get this:
男爵将乘坐我的船在几天内到达港口。
The Baron will arrive in port aboard my own ship in a matter of days.
不如带我去El Libre这样我们就能把枪卖了?
So how about taking me to El Libre so we can close the deal for the guns?
时间和潮汐，你知道的。
Time and tide, you know.
把臭味洗掉，带到下面去。
Wash the stink off them and take them below.
把这个消息传下去。
Pass the word along.
天黑的时候，我们把他们带到小船上……然后把他们送到船上。跟我来。
When it's dark, we'll take them to the small boat... and row them out to their ship. Come with me.
现在，你知道计划是什么了。
Now, you know what the plan is.
剩下的会和我的弟兄们一起去捕鱼…站在海盗船旁边接受武器。
The rest will join my lads at the fishing boats... and stand by the pirate vessel to receive the guns.
如果海盗拒绝交出他们呢?
Suppose the pirates refuse to give them up?
我会用刀指着瓦洛船长的喉咙。
I'll keep my knife at Captain Vallo's throat.
要么他会下令交出枪支…否则他再也不会下命令了。
Either he'll give the order to hand over the guns... or he'll never give another order.
你是在割我们的喉咙，巴勃罗·墨菲，不是他的。
You're cutting our throats, Pablo Murphy, not his.
我喜欢你的勇气，巴勃罗，但不喜欢你的计划。
I like your nerve, Pablo, but not your plan.
要我说，我们得在格鲁达男爵来之前拿到枪，占领宫殿。
I say we've got to get the guns and take the palace before Baron Gruda gets here.
我觉得我们需要的不仅仅是枪。我们需要El Libre来领导我们。
And I say we need more than guns. We need El Libre to lead us.
你们女人不会面对现实。El Libre被捕了。
You women won't face facts. El Libre's been captured.
面对事实的方法就是拯救他。
The way to face facts is to rescue him.
救他?从国王的监狱里?不可能的。
Rescue him? From the King's prison? Impossible.
对于一个带着三十名机枪手和战斗人员的绝望之人来说是不可能的。
Not for a desperate man with a 30-gunner and a fighting crew.
海盗营救El Libre?
A pirate rescue for El Libre?
那就是把他从油锅里捞出来扔进火里。
That'd be taking him from the frying pan and throwing him into the fire.
-我们会用自己的方式处理。——脸!
- We'll handle this our own way. - About face!
在这里。
Get over here.
有一个会议!门,快!
There's a meeting! The door, quick!
出去!另一扇门!
Out! The other door!
如果我放了你，你能帮我吗?
If I release you, can I count on your help?
你的薪水会很高的。
You'll be well paid.
你错判了我们的人。
You misjudged our men.
不要误判我们的女人。
Don't misjudge our women.
-这里还有一扇门。——在哪里?
- Another door here. - Where?
跟我来。
Follow me.
-怎么回事?-从市场回来的船长。
- What's all the shooting? - The Skipper coming back from market.
我有预感我们要出海了。
I have a feeling we'll be putting out to sea.
起重机锚。人所有的画布。看起来活泼!
Hoist anchor. Man all canvas. Look lively!
男人的码!
Man the yards!
准备火!
Prepare to fire!
火!
Fire one!
火两个!
Fire two!
给格鲁达男爵的船发信号，让他开舷。我们中的一个可以把她从水里弄出来。
Signal Baron Gruda's ship for a broadside. One of us can knock her out of the water.
海岸炮台要求对他们进行舷侧攻击，贝洛斯先生。
Shore battery's asking for a broadside against them, Mr. Bellows.
你还在等什么，流口水的白痴?
What are you waiting for, drooling idiot?
-给他们开舷炮!-是，是，先生!舷侧有一条船过来了!
- Give 'em a broadside! - Aye, aye, sir! One broadside coming up!
拍摄好,小伙子。的目的。
Good shooting, lads. Well aimed.
船长，这是你在市场上买的吗?
Skipper, be that what thou bought at market?
带这位女士下去，让她舒服点。
Take the lady below and make her comfortable.
谢谢你,队长。
Thank you, Captain.
英勇的瓦洛船长，是吗，小伙子们?
The gallant Captain Vallo, eh, lads?
是El Libre吗?
Be that bit of fluff El Libre?
这是我们找到他的线索。
That's the bit of fluff that's taking us to him.
他被关在圣佩罗岛上，离这里只有一天的航程。
He's being held on the Island of San Perot, only a day's sailing from here.
谁在帮我们抓他，船长?
Who's holding him for us, Skipper?
国王的军队。在军事监狱里。现在，还有什么比这更甜蜜的呢?
The King's troop. In the military prison. Now, what could be sweeter, lads?
我们把他从国王的手下偷走，再卖回给国王的手下。
We'll steal him from the King's men, and sell him back to a king's man.
-但你当真打算……-把我们送进国王的监狱?
- But be thou seriously planning to... - Walk us into a king's prison?
当然不是，卑微的风箱，当然不是。
Why, not at all, Humble Bellows, not at all.
围过来，小伙子们，围过来!
Gather round, lads, gather round!
-我的，我的，好漂亮的一把刀。-你想仔细看看吗?
- My, my, what a pretty knife. - Would you like a closer look?
让我们让这个锅看起来像一条线上的船!
Let's keep this pot looking like a ship of the line!
来这里。
Come up here.
开始干吧!
Hop to it!
我是来谈El Libre的。
I came up to talk about El Libre.
——继续。我在听。-你有办法救他吗?
- Go ahead. I'm listening. - You have a plan to save him?
一个计划和一个价格。仅枪支就需要5万美元。
A plan and a price. Guns alone will cost 50,000.
这对买枪来说可是一大笔钱。El Libre你要价多少?
That's a great deal of money for guns. How much are you asking for El Libre?
哦，是的， El Libre
Oh, yes, El Libre.
我会白白把他扔进去的。
I'll throw him in for nothing.
很好,队长。
Very well, Captain.
我将设法与他安排这笔钱。
I'll see that the money is arranged with him.
你可以相信他会遵守协议的。
You may be sure that he'll honor the agreement.
你的计划是什么?
What's your plan?
你昨晚为什么闩上小屋的门?
Why did you bolt your cabin door last night?
如果你知道它是栓的，你一定试过。
If you know it was bolted, you must've tried it.
如果你试过，你就知道为什么它是闩上的。
And if you tried it, you know why it was bolted.
你打算怎么得到El Libre?
How do you propose to get El Libre?
你的门只对他敞开吗?
Is your door open only to him?
你是什么意思?
What do you mean?
这么多对一个人的关注不可能完全是政治性的。
So much concern about one man can't be entirely political.
他是你的爱人。
He's your lover.
不。
No.
他是我的父亲。
He's my father.
船长!
Captain!
土地!
Land ho!
站起来，小伙子们。注意!
On your feet, lads. Attention!
你们应该是国王的臣民，而不是吟游诗人。
You're supposed to be king's men, not bard slabs.
看起来你就该穿制服。
Look like you belong in those uniforms.
奥霍，通知守军格鲁达男爵已经来逮捕El Libre了。
Ojo, signal to the garrison that Baron Gruda has arrived... to take El Libre into custody.
-那我父亲呢?-我命令你待在下面。
- What about my father? - I ordered you to stay below.
它们在发出什么信号?
What are they signaling?
卫戍指挥官希望设宴款待格鲁达男爵。
The garrison commander wishes to give a dinner in honor of Baron Gruda.
我们该怎么办?
What are we going to do?
当然，我们会接受。
We're going to accept, of course.
格鲁达男爵和他的小宝贝…船上留下的衣服足够骗过国王了
Baron Gruda and his bit of fluff... left enough clothes onboard to fool the King himself.
如果有人认出我们…我们会跳脱衣舞，让El Libre吃点苦头。
If anyone recognizes us... we'll be stripping for action and taking El Libre the hard way.
好多人啊，上尉。一群好男人。
A fine body of men, Captain. A fine body of men.
格鲁达男爵阁下和他的政党。
His Excellency Baron Gruda and party.
欢迎,阁下。
Welcome, Your Excellency.
我们大家都很荣幸终于见到您了。
It is a great honor for all of us to meet you at last.
你能接受我们的款待，我们感到非常高兴。
It gives us great pleasure that you accept our hospitality.
恰恰相反，亲爱的上校，是我被录取了。
On the contrary, my dear Colonel, it is I who am accepted.
哦，不，阁下。我是幸运的。
Oh, no, Your Excellency. I am the lucky one.
眼镜蛇总督指示我处决El Libre
I had instructions from the Governor of Cobra to execute El Libre.
当我收到你的信息时，我正准备这么做。
I was on the verge of doing so when I got your message.
州长是个白痴!我可能会取代他……和一个军人。
The Governor is an idiot! I may replace him... with a military man.
-我亲爱的男爵。-亲爱的上校。
- My dear Baron. - My dear Colonel.
我可以把你介绍给我们的客人吗?-当然可以。
- May I introduce you to our guests? - By all means.
——阁下。——阁下。
- Your Excellency. - Your Excellency.
但我在这里收国王的税太难了。
But I have so much trouble collecting the King's taxes here.
告诉我,计数。人们在家里怎么付款?
Tell me, Count. How do the people pay at home?
通过鼻子!他们花了大价钱!
Through the nose! They pay through the nose!
真是太好了!
That's really very good!
这个游戏我们还要玩多久?
How long do we have to play this game?
直到上校决定交出El Libre
Till the Colonel decides to hand over El Libre.
我害怕。
I am frightened.
伯爵一定是你的心头好。
The Count must be a constant delight to you.
他真是太有趣了。
He's really too funny for words.
事实上他是。
Indeed he is.
请告诉我们，伯爵。
Do tell us, Count.
最近女王出门都穿什么?
What does the Queen wear when she goes out these days?
伯爵总说王后把国王累坏了。
The Count always says the Queen wears the King out.
你是最聪明的人!
You are the wittiest man!
女士们先生们，请注意。
Ladies and gentlemen, may I have your attention, please.
为了纪念格鲁达男爵的来访……圣西奥驻军的军官们为他准备了一份小礼物。
To commemorate the honor Baron Gruda has done us by his visit... the officers of the Saint Theo garrison have arranged a little gift for him.
请大家到这边来好吗?
Will everyone come this way, please?
在左边……有热爱民主和人民的El Libre
On the left... you have that great lover of democracy and the people, El Libre.
而在右边，那位杰出的科学家…教授审慎。
And on the right, that distinguished scientist... Professor Prudence.
两个人都像老鼠被夹子夹住了一样……密谋破坏陛下的荣耀。
Both caught like rats in a trap... conspiring against the greater glory of His Majesty.
但是多亏了像格鲁达男爵这样的政治家…这样的人和这样的思想很快就会被摧毁。
But thanks to statesmen like Baron Gruda... such men and such ideas will soon be destroyed.
作为一位杰出的科学家……我可以向你保证，一个想法没有可以被摧毁的物理性质。
As a distinguished scientist... I can assure you an idea has no physical properties which can be destroyed.
作为一个热爱民主和人民的人，我可以向你保证……它们都能挺过你微不足道的努力。
As a lover of democracy and the people, I can assure you... both will survive your puny efforts.
作为一名政治家，我可以向你保证，没有人能预知未来。
As a statesman, I can assure you that no one can foretell the future.
然而，你现在的命运对我来说很清楚…作为我身边这位美丽女士的脸。
However, your fate at present is as clear to me... as the face of this beautiful lady at my side.
万岁!
Bravo!
谢谢您，阁下。
Thank you, Your Excellency.
是的。她很漂亮。
Yes. She is very beautiful.
阁下说得有道理。
His Excellency has a point.
明明我们的命运就掌握在他手里，还跟命运吵架真是愚蠢。
It's foolish to quarrel with fate when ours is so clearly in his hands.
带他们出去，让格鲁达男爵满意。
Take them outside and hold them for Baron Gruda's pleasure.
亲爱的上校，谢谢你今晚的款待。
My dear Colonel, thank you for a most rewarding evening.
-现在我们必须走了。-这绝不是结束。
- And now we must go. - It is by no means over.
我安排了一场特别的娱乐活动…为了这个特别的时刻。
I've arranged a very special entertainment... for this very special occasion.
是那个被我们绑架勒索的女人。
It's that dame we held for ransom.
弃船。
Abandon ship.
-谢谢你，亲爱的上校。——阁下!
- Thank you, my dear Colonel. - Your Excellency!
-可是，我亲爱的男爵!-愉快的夜晚，上校。
- But, my dear Baron! - Wonderful evening, Colonel.
法洛!
Vallo!
但是,阁下。
But, Your Excellency.
意想不到的国际事务。我们外交官也经常遇到这种事。
Unexpected international affairs. Happens to us diplomats all the time.
-把犯人放到我的马车里。-是，是，先生。
- Put the prisoners in my carriage. - Aye, aye, sir.
我真希望国王能听到，大人。
I do hope the King will hear about this, Your Excellency.
别担心，他会的。
Don't worry, he will.
放开我，你们这些污染的虾。
Unclutch me, you polluted shrimp.
阻止他，你们这些傻瓜!
Stop him, you fools!
他是深红海盗!
He's the Crimson Pirate!
深红色的海盗?
The Crimson Pirate?
深红色的海盗!
The Crimson Pirate!
把上校带到安全的地方。快,男人。
Take the Colonel to safety. Quick, man.
-带上校去安全的地方!-放开我，你们这些蠢货!
- Take the Colonel to safety! - Let me go, you fools!
别担心,上校。我会处理好一切的!
Don't worry, Colonel. I'll take care of everything!
拉威尔公民，救救伯爵!-救救伯爵!
- Citizen Ravel, save the Count! - Save the Count!
——陛下!陛下!-干得好，上尉。
- Sire! Sire! - Good work, Captain.
阻止他!那是深红海盗!
Stop him! There's the Crimson Pirate!
船长!
Captain!
军官们在造反。摧毁他们!
The officers are mutinying. Crush them!
摧毁他们!来吧!
Crush them! Come on!
声音的攻击!
Sound the attack!
代管。不要让步。保护妇女和儿童。
Hold the fort. Don't give an inch. Protect the women and children.
援军马上就到。锁的大门!不要让任何人出去。
Reinforcements are on the way. Lock the gates! Let no one out.
锁的大门!不要让任何人出去!
Lock the gates! Let no one out!
国王万岁!
Long live the King!
我想我们以前没见过面。我叫普律当丝。
I don't think we've met. My name is Prudence.
瓦洛船长，愿为您效劳。
Captain Vallo, at your service.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
你笑什么?
What are you grinning at?
所以，我有一个光环。你怕我变得心软。
So, I'm getting a halo. You're afraid I'm getting soft.
是的,你错了。
Yeah, you're wrong.
只是这是一种新的雀跃。这些人真让我心烦。
It's just that this is a new kind of caper. These people are getting on my nerves.
El Libre和他女儿纯粹是公事公办。
El Libre and his daughter are strictly business.
他们没有把我锁起来。我把他们锁起来了。
They haven't got me chained. I've got them chained.
我很快就能摆脱他们了。
I'll be rid of them soon enough.
明天，我会亲自交给格鲁达男爵。
Tomorrow, I'm delivering them to Baron Gruda personally.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
这个女孩吗?
The girl?
那女孩呢?
What about the girl?
她让我很生气。
She's getting under my skin.
她给我灌输了很多疯狂的想法。
She's putting crazy ideas in my head.
她打开了我的心。她离我太近了。
She's unlocked my heart. She's getting too close to me.
她让我着迷了。
She's got me hooked.
她是盲目的。
She's blind.
我是盲目的。你是盲目的。
I'm blind. You're blind.
盲人是谁?
Who's blind?
哦!爱情是盲目的。
Oh! Love is blind.
我没有恋爱!
I am not in love!
停住!
Avast there!
我告诉过你不要这么吵。现在船长会抓到她的。
I told you not to make so much noise. Now the Skipper will get her.
-他总是这样。-没人能得到她。
- He always does. - Nobody will get her.
解开。动!
Untie the others. Move!
有什么事吗?我在找点乐子。
What's up? I'm having a little fun.
-拜托，船长。让我们找点乐子吧。-你想独享她吗?
- Come on, Skipper. Let us have some fun. - You want her all to yourself?
-你为什么不加入呢?-你为什么不自己试试?
- Why don't you join the fun? - Why don't you try yourself?
-你总是说你去不了。-总是工作，没有乐趣。
- You always tell that you couldn't make it. - Always work and no fun.
贝洛斯先生，把三个都带下去，把舱室钥匙给我。
Mr. Bellows, take all three below and bring me the cabin keys.
如果你能原谅我指出来的话，船长…我们不能把一个漂亮女人留在船上不受骚扰。
If you'll forgive my pointing it out, Skipper... we can't leave a pretty woman unmolested aboard ship.
这会给盗版带来坏名声。
It will give piracy a bad name.
你在挑战我的命令吗?
Are you challenging my orders?
我绝不会那么做的，船长…但你还是要把这些鸽子卖给格鲁达男爵……我想先跟他们玩玩也无妨。
I'd never do that, Skipper... but seeing thou is selling these pigeons to Baron Gruda anyway... I thought there could be no harm to sport with them a bit first.
没有进攻,队长。
No offense, Skipper.
我明天就让你在眼镜蛇号上岸，把枪给你。
I'm putting you ashore tomorrow at Cobra and giving you the guns.
你们所有的人。
All of you.
别谢我就行。
Just don't thank me.
队长。
Skipper.
是的，那是我们的船。格鲁达男爵在等着。
Yes, there's our ship. With Baron Gruda waiting.
难道他不讨厌为El Libre付钱吗?当他发现我们把他从国王的监狱里偷出来
Won't he hate paying for El Libre... when he finds out we stole him out of one of the King's own prisons?
-我们将坚持到天黑。-是，是，船长。
- We'll heave to onto the point till nightfall. - Aye, aye, Skipper.
Slimey。
Slimey.
让我们看你游到那边的岛上去。-是的，然后又回来了。
- Let's see thee swim to yonder island. - Aye, and back again.
如果我的计划成功，格鲁达男爵会亲自护送你回去。
If my plan works, Baron Gruda himself will escort thee back.
我要你带个口信给他。
I've a message for thee to give to him.
照做，等我当上船长…你将成为大副。
Do it, and when I am skipper... thou wilt be first mate.
波纹管先生……
Mr. Bellows...
-鲨鱼呢?-他们从不攻击人。
- what about sharks? - They never attack a man.
除非他先攻击他们。
Unless he attacks them first.
——州长。——男爵?
- Governor. - Baron?
-让他去厨房喂他。——厨房。喂他。
- Send him to the kitchen and feed him. - Kitchen. Feed him.
你会为他们准备好10万金币弗罗林。
You'll have the 100,000 gold florin ready for them.
只要阁下下令。
Whatever Your Excellency orders.
-但这纯粹是盗版。我向你保证…我要让他的女儿埃尔·利布雷，他杰出的同谋者……我们的船，我们的枪，那些海盗，还有瓦洛船长，连一个苏都没付。
- But this is sheer piracy. - I assure you... I shall have El Libre, his daughter, his distinguished conspirator... our ship, our guns, the pirates, and Captain Vallo, without paying a sou.
-那为什么是10万?我说，把钱准备好。
- Then why 100,000? - Have the money ready, I said.
大副认为他能毁掉瓦洛，但他的计划可能会失败。
The first mate thinks he can undo Vallo, but his plan may fail.
即使我们要付钱，这样的运货价格翻倍也算便宜了。
Even if we have to pay, such a haul would be cheap at double the price.
顺便说一下…我要一桶这个，好好下药。
By the way... I shall want a barrel of this, well drugged.
-你干掉了瓦洛船长?——没有。
- You disposed of Captain Vallo? - No.
有必要先让船员们知道他的情况。
It will be necessary to expose him to the crew first.
如果你听从了我的指示，我很快就会这么做的。
Which I'll be doing soon enough, if thou has followed my instructions.
这封信。
To the letter.
和钱吗?请原谅我的急躁。
And the money? If you'll forgive my impatience.
明天早上它会等着你的。
It will be waiting for you in the morning.
与此同时，我把自己交给你作为担保。
Meanwhile, I place myself in your hands as security for it.
很好。
Very well.
但我提醒你，他们两手空空的时候是杀人的。
But I remind thee, they be murderous hands when they're empty.
把大人藏在下面。
Hide His Excellency below.
一旦上层安全了，奥乔就会带着小船在下面待命。
As soon as it's clear topside, Ojo will stand by below with a small boat.
靠岸很短。打电话给你的父亲。
It's a short pull to shore. Call your father.
加入我们吧。加入我们的行列。
Come with us. Join us.
不。
No.
但是你想要。我知道你想。
But you want to. I know you want to.
你错了。
You're wrong.
对我没有任何好处。让你的父亲。
There's nothing in it for me. Get your father.
那你为什么放我们自由?
Then why are you setting us free?
-我信守诺言，即使是愚蠢的诺言。-你没有承诺。
- I keep my promises, even foolish ones. - You made no promise.
你说要把我们卖了，你不能这么做。
You made a deal to sell us, and you can't do it.
好吧,。我这么做是为了你。我们就到这里吧。
All right, then. I'm doing it for you. Let's leave it at that.
不,法洛。我们不能就这么算了。
No, Vallo. We can't leave it at that.
你是一个战士。与我们战斗。
You're a fighter. Fight with us.
-争取一些体面的东西。——而不是我。
- Fight for something decent. - Not I.
在我的一生中，我看到不公正和不诚实打着体面的旗号。
All my life I've watched injustice and dishonesty fly the flag of decency.
-我不信任他们。-你不信任我吗?
- I don't trust them. - Don't you trust me?
你不相信我们之间的感情吗?
Don't you trust what we have for each other?
我们对彼此的感情我们必须克服。
What we have for each other we'll have to get over.
我们可以吗?
Can we?
你是对的。我不会让你走的。
You're right. I won't let you go.
在我的船上，我们是属于一起的。我们会找到办法的。
We belong together here, aboard my ship. We'll find a way.
但这是不可能的。
But that's not possible.
-我不能待在这里。你没有看见吗?-我明白了。
- I can't stay here. Don't you see? - Yes, I see.
现在，你终于也看到了。
And now, at last, you see it, too.
你有你的世界，我有我的。
You've got your world, and I've got mine.
好吧,先生们。
All right, gentlemen.
坐下来。
Sit down.
教授，你稍后带着巴勃罗·墨菲和枪上岸。
Professor, you'll go ashore later with Pablo Murphy and the guns.
——正确的。-继续自言自语，大声说。
- Right. - Keep talking to yourself, loudly.
我想让我的人以为你们还在这里。
I want my men to think you're all still here.
这对我来说不是问题。
That's no problem for me.
记住，这是个危险的游戏。
Now, remember, this is a dangerous game.
如果我的人屈服了，他们会割了你的喉咙，还有我的。
If my men tumble to it, they'll slit your throats, and mine, too.
我不喜欢这样，上尉。
I don't like it, Captain.
我们不能让你独自面对他们。加入我们吧。
We can't leave you to face them alone. Come with us.
父亲……不喜欢。
Father... don't.
停住!人的枪!
Avast! Man the guns!
在甲板上,你拭子!
Topside, you swabs!
的帮助!
Help!
别急，船长，恕我冒昧。
Not so fast, Skipper, if you'll pardon the intrusion.
你把我卖给了一个国王的仆从，卑微的风箱。
You've sold me, Humble Bellows, and to a king's flunky.
看不见你。
Aye.
我谦虚地认为，没有人能像海盗一样飞翔……不愿意出卖自己的朋友，爱人和母亲的人。
'Tis my modest opinion that no man can fly pirate's colors... who's not willing to sell his friend, his sweetheart, or his mother.
-说得好，贝洛斯先生。-说得难听。
- Well spoken, Mr. Bellows. - Foul spoken it is.
你的手碰到了队长的背。
You've turned your hand against your Captain's back.
黄色从来不是海盗的颜色。
Yellow was never a pirate's color.
拯救一个美丽的少女也不是海盗的行为。
Nor rescuing a fair maiden a pirate caper.
看不见你。
Aye.
这是真的。我驶出了我的纵深……但只是为了为我们大家探索新的领域。
It's true. I sailed beyond my depth... but only to sound out new waters for the lot of us.
如果我们都饿死了，我就不会把你卖了。
If we'd have starved to death, I'd have never sold a man jack of you.
聚集,小伙子。这不是最后一次海盗活动。
Gather round, lads. This isn't the last of the pirate capers.
这是最后的你和你的刺山柑……因为当你试图剥夺我们的战利品时，它已经被付诸表决了。
'Tis the last of thee and of thy capers... for 'twas put to the vote whilst thee was trying to deprive us of our loot.
叶违反了海盗守则，放了一条肥鱼。
Ye violated the pirate code by letting a fat fish off the hook.
全体投票决定，你被剥夺指挥权……并根据海盗法被判乘小船漂流没有食物和水。
By vote of all, ye are deprived of command... and sentenced under piratical law to be cast adrift in a small boat... without food or water.
一个绝妙的决定，贝洛斯先生。快判死刑
A splendid decision, Mr. Bellows. Quick justice and certain death.
也许你可以省下国王绞死这个博学的傻瓜的代价……让他和瓦洛船长作伴。
Perhaps you'd save the King the expense of hanging this learned fool... and let him keep Captain Vallo company.
你有慷慨的选择。
Thou hast a generous choice.
绞刑架或大海。
The gallows or the sea.
如果它不挤你的话。
If it won't crowd you.
我宁愿你不来，但我也不想显得不好客。
I'd rather you weren't coming, but I don't want to seem inhospitable.
至于你…既然我没有声音反对你们船长的轻罪……把你的手交给你的新船长，你就会得到宽恕。
As for thee... since I have no voice to raise against thy Captain's misdemeanors... thee will be pardoned by giving thy hand to thy new skipper.
说你什么?我们可以解开你的绳索吗?
What say thee? Shall we loose thy bonds?
抑制他的嚣张气焰。
Cut him loose.
这是完成,队长。我们让他们漂流。
It's done, Skipper. We set them adrift.
早潮将带他们出海。
The morning tide will take them out to sea.
等等!这需要庆祝一下，对吧，贝洛斯先生?
Wait! This calls for a celebration, eh, Mr. Bellows?
我的船上有一桶朗姆酒。直接从总督的酒窖里拿的。
I've a keg of rum aboard my boat. Straight from the Governor's own cellar.
说什么?
What say?
看不见你。
Aye.
我想喝一杯。
I could use a drink.
来吧,小伙子们!把朗姆酒弄上船。
Come on, lads! Get the rum aboard.
把我的拿去船长的舱房。
Bring mine to the Captain's cabin.
这是陆地的尽头。我们世界的末日。
There's the end of land. The end of our world.
从现在开始，饥饿，干渴，最终倾覆。
From now on, it's starve, thirst, and finally capsize.
我一直在思考这个问题。
I've been meditating on just that.
倾覆是解决问题的办法。这是毫无疑问的。
Capsizing is the solution of our problem. There's no doubt about it.
-请跟我来。-坐下，你这个傻瓜!
- If you'll follow me, please. - Sit down, you fool!
坐下来,你……
Sit down, you...
它的工作原理。
It works.
美好的亚里士多德。
Good old Aristotle.
2000多年前，他写道:
Over 2,000 years ago, he wrote:
金属容器可以在水下保持空气，而不用填充。
"A metallic vessel will retain air underwater without filling. "
但我自己对此做了一些研究……同时设计一艘我称之为“海底船”的船。
But I myself have done some research on the subject... while designing a craft which I call an undersea boat.
-你怎么知道这是无懈可击的?-在科学方面，我的儿子…一个人不做实验就什么都不知道。
- How did you know this was airtight? - In science, my son... one knows nothing until one experiments.
我们现在可以断定我们是在呼吸。
We may now conclude that we are breathing.
让我们尽快上岸吧。
Let us walk ashore as quickly as possible.
我估计这里的空气足够我们呼吸几分钟。
I compute there's sufficient air to last us several minutes.
当然，前提是我们不浪费氧气说话。
Providing we don't waste our oxygen talking, of course.
-那好吧。闭嘴!——如此。
- All right, then. Shut up! - Quite so.
你没必要把整个守军都带出来。我自己干的。
You needn't have brought out the whole garrison. I did the job myself.
他们这次醒来就不会那么爱玩了。
They won't be so playful when they wake up this time.
好吧。叫醒他们。
All right. Wake them up.
让他们清醒，然后带他们去海盗船。
Sober them up and take them to the pirate ship.
跟他们一起翻到一边去!
Over the side with them!
我很抱歉，伙计们。我谦卑地道歉。
Sorry I be for this, mates. And I humbly apologize.
如果瓦洛当船长就不会发生这种事。
'Twould never have happened with Vallo as skipper.
他违反了海盗守则，必须离开。
He violated a pirate code and he had to go.
但是他像海盗一样去了。我们像鱼一样前进。
But he went like a pirate. We're going like fish.
我不能原谅我自己。
I can't forgive myself for that.
国王的走狗把谦卑的风箱变成了猴子。
King's flunky made a monkey of Humble Bellows.
-老派海盗。-够了!
- Pirate of the old school. - Enough of that!
提升他们!
Hoist them!
派一组船员上船，重新排查。
Put a crew aboard this ship and have her re-canvased.
我要她在我离开时准备好起航。
I want her ready to sail when I leave.
给他们足够的面包和水让他们活下去。
Give them just enough bread and water to keep them alive.
他们会从国王那里得到一大笔赏金。
They'll fetch a good bounty from the King.
喂。巴勃罗·墨菲。
Ahoy. Pablo Murphy.
-嗯，我会…-把我们从铁链上弄下来。
- Well, I'll be... - Get us out of these chains.
你让我们卷入了这么多，你这个谎话连篇的大嘴巴?
After all you got us into, you lying blabbermouth?
让你自己摆脱它。
Get yourself out of it.
——巴勃罗·墨菲。-最后说一次，离我们远点
- Pablo Murphy. - For the last time, get away from us.
用你的脑子想想，我没有出卖El Libre
Get it through that head of yours, I didn't sell El Libre.
-我向你保证…-我们可以亲眼看到他做了什么。
- Let me assure... - We can see for ourselves what he's done.
如果我们走我的路，El Libre就不会死。
If we'd gone my way, El Libre wouldn't be dead.
康斯韦洛不会被囚禁在宫殿里……我们就有枪来阻止格鲁达的人碾压我们。
Consuelo wouldn't be held captive in the palace... and we'd have guns to stop Gruda's men from crushing us.
抓住它,先生们。士兵。
Hold it, gentlemen. Soldiers.
格鲁达男爵下令，所有捕鱼活动都将在武装护卫下进行。
By order of Baron Gruda, all fishing will be done under armed escort.
所有的鱼都要交给总督。
The entire catch to be turned over to the Governor.
-我们还剩下什么?——这是诱饵。
- What'll be left for us? - The bait.
那样的话，我们就不钓鱼了。
In that case, we'll do no fishing.
任何更多的反对意见?
Any more objections?
剩下的人去州长的码头。行动起来!
The rest of you proceed to the Governor's dock. Get moving!
带他去堡垒。
Take him to the fortress.
这种方式。
This way.
-嘿，回来排队。-跟着那些船。
- Hey, there, back in line. - Follow those boats.
之后他们!
After them!
我们走吧。
Let's go.
-都安排好了吗?-遵命，阁下。
- Is everything arranged? - Just as you ordered, Excellency.
你一夜之间就打垮了叛军。国王欠你太多了。
You've broken the back of the rebellion overnight. The King owes you much.
他会付出代价的。我甚至可以在干掉瓦洛船长时拿到全部赏金…因为他在试图拯救El Libre的时候被自己的人杀死了。
He will pay it. I may even be able to collect the full bounty on Captain Vallo... for he was killed by his own men while trying to save El Libre.
别难过，亲爱的。
Don't be upset, my dear.
您将在这里形成新的附件。你要嫁给总督。
You'll form new attachments here. You're to marry the Governor.
我死后，你将通过她来统治，州长。
After I'm gone, you'll rule through her, Governor.
你会命令你的人民耕种他们的土地，捕鱼他们的海洋…为了国王更大的荣耀。
You'll order your people to till their fields and fish their seas... for the greater glory of the King.
-我宁愿死。-不，你是最后一个死的。
- I'd die first. - No, you'll die last.
首先你要看着你的人一个接一个离开。
First you'll watch your people go one by one.
总有一天我会杀了你。
Someday I'll kill you.
官!
Officer!
这些方法很快就会使她苏醒过来。
These methods will bring her round soon.
我不希望她在结婚前自杀。
I shouldn't like her to kill herself before she marries.
她不是那种人。她会嫁给你，伺机毒死你。
She's not the type. She'll marry you and wait for a chance to poison you.
听起来不像是理想的婚姻。难道我们不能放弃它吗?
It doesn't sound like an ideal marriage. Couldn't we dispense with that?
吃太多会让我的肝脏不舒服。
Too much of it upsets my liver.
不是你的肝脏。这是你的的心。太软了。
It's not your liver. It's your heart. It's much too soft.
今晚，人民将埋葬El Libre
Tonight the people bury El Libre.
我要一张布告贴在送葬队伍行进的路上。宣布你与El Libre的女儿结婚。
I want a proclamation posted in the path of the funeral procession... announcing your marriage to the daughter of El Libre.
阁下!
Excellency!
人们将被要求参加并提供娱乐。让它成为一个欢乐的日子。
People will be required to attend and provide entertainment... to make it a day of rejoicing.
我们会让他们填满皇家粮仓…带着一万袋粮食作为礼物。
We'll have them fill the royal grain warehouse... with 10,000 sacks of grain as a present.
你学习得很快。
You're learning fast.
仪式结束后，我将把我的部队和祝福留给你们，然后离开。
After the ceremony, I'll leave you my troops and my blessings, and depart.
除了已故的瓦洛，这是一项最无聊的任务。
Except for the late, lamented Vallo, this has been a most boring assignment.
上路吧，猪!已宣布大赦所有囚犯。
On your way, pig! Amnesty has been declared for all prisoners.
格鲁达男爵会给你一个在婚礼上表达忠诚的机会。
Baron Gruda will give you a chance to show allegiance at the wedding.
Gruda。
Gruda.
格鲁达，总有一天我会杀了你。
Gruda, someday I'll kill you.
我要杀了你!
I'll kill you!
-所以现在是婚姻了，是吗?-康丝埃洛不会这么做的。
- So it's a marriage now, is it? - Consuelo will never do it.
看!一万袋粮食给总督。
Look! 10,000 sacks of grain for the Governor.
不是我的!
Not mine!
所以我们应该庆幸，是吗?
So we're to rejoice, are we?
格鲁达男爵破坏了公共财产…可判处死刑的罪行无论是罪犯还是同谋。
Baron Gruda has made the defacing of public property... an offense punishable by death... both for the culprit and the accomplices.
中士，把这些人集合起来。
Sergeant, round up these people.
-你打算怎么做?-这不关我的事
- What are you going to do about it? - It's no concern of mine.
-你要拿她怎么办?-想办法把她弄出来
- What are you going to do about her? - Get her out of it, somehow.
一个人对抗一千名士兵?
Alone, against 1,000 troops?
-一定有办法的。——有。
- There must be a way. - There is.
这是一个简单的逻辑问题。我们需要盟国。
It's a question of simple logic. We need allies.
这些人需要自由。让我们帮助他们得到它。
These people need freedom. Let's help them get it.
我唯一感兴趣的是康丝薇洛的自由。
The only freedom I'm interested in is Consuelo's.
在她的人民获得自由之前她是不会同意获得自由的。
She'll never consent to be free until her people are free.
不可能的。
Impossible.
他们对付不了格鲁达的精锐部队。
They don't have a chance against Gruda's crack troops.
科学告诉我们，没有什么是不可能的。
Science has learned that nothing is impossible.
不久前，我看到一艘船在法国的天空中航行……被一个充满空气的大袋子支撑着它比空气还轻。
Not long ago, I saw a ship sailing through the skies of France... supported by a great bag filled with air that was lighter than air.
我的一个朋友发明了一种可以炸开高山的液体。
A friend of mine has invented a liquid that can blast away mountains.
我已经完成了一艘能在水下航行的船的计划。
I have completed plans for a boat that can sail underneath the water.
谁知道我们会完成什么……反对过时的格鲁达男爵和他过时的世界?
Who knows what we may accomplish... against the outdated Baron Gruda and his outdated world?
我们只需要这些人的帮助…一点想象力，和灵巧的手指偷一些基本的材料。
All we need is the help of these people... a little imagination, and deft fingers with which to steal a few basic materials.
男爵认为我们完蛋了。
The Baron thinks we're finished.
我们要让他继续这么想。
We're going to let him go on thinking so.
我们会按订单填满皇家粮仓。
We'll fill the royal grain warehouse as ordered.
但有了教授的天才种子。
But with the seeds of the Professor's genius.
-你说什么?男爵拥有最多的武器。
- I beg your pardon? - The Baron has the most weapons.
但我们会有最新的。
But we'll have the newest.
可以移动山脉的炸药。船:在空中飞行的船
An explosive that moves mountains. A ship that flies through the air.
下周日就能飞起来的船?不可能的。
A ship that flies through the air by next Sunday? Impossible.
一位伟人曾对我说:
A great man once said to me:
“科学已经知道，没有什么是不可能的。”
"Science has learned that nothing is impossible. "
小伙子们，姑娘们，围过来。
Gather round, lads and lasses.
我们将向你们的战士和工人展示摆脱旧敌人的新方法。
We'll show your fighters and workers new ways to get rid of old enemies.
闻起来不对劲。
It doesn't smell right.
一万袋粮食已运进仓库。
10,000 sacks of grain have been brought into the warehouse.
把他们偷运出去的隧道已经打通了。
The tunnel to smuggle them out is complete.
这个岛屿在走私现代化武器方面取得了进展。而你依然站在那里，动弹不得……炖菜没有结果。
The island is making headway with the modern weapons to smuggle in... and still you stand and stir... that stew with no result.
我的朋友没有给我配方……简单的成分。主要是氮和甘油。
My friend sent me no formula to go on... simply the ingredients. Principally nitrogen and glycerin.
不管怎样，我不确定我是否想去发现它。
Anyway, I'm not really sure I want to discover it.
如果它能移走一座山，我怎么知道它不会移走一座岛?
If it can remove a mountain, how do I know it won't remove an island?
“在科学上，不做实验什么都不知道。”
"In science, one knows nothing unless one experiments. "
我希望你别再引用我的话了。
I wish you'd stop quoting me.
就是这样。
That's it.
士兵们!
Soldiers!
别被那件事打倒。
Don't fall down with that.
即使他们朝你开枪。
Even if they shoot you.
早上小心别充气过度。
Be careful you don't over-inflate this in the morning.
我们已经把墙上的支架切到了极限。
We've cut the wall braces to the breaking point.
但我们不希望它们在信号发出前崩溃。
But we don't want them to collapse before the signal.
记得……在康苏埃洛安全离开格鲁达男爵之前不会发出信号。
Remember... there'll be no signal given till Consuelo's gotten safely away from Baron Gruda.
小心。
Careful.
液体炸药。
The liquid explosive.
-就剩下这些了吗?-我改进了一下公式。
- Is that all that's left? - I've improved a bit on the formula.
浓缩了1000倍。
This is concentrated 1,000 times.
请。
Please.
据报道，皇家粮仓已经满仓了，阁下。
The royal grain warehouse is reported full to capacity, Your Excellency.
你怎么能让他们屈服。
Amazing how you brought them to their knees.
孩子不打不成器。永远不要忘记，我亲爱的州长。
Spare the rod and spoil the child. Never forget that, my dear Governor.
我们继续举行婚礼吧。
Let's get on with the wedding ceremony.
首先，岛上的未婚女孩为新娘献上鲜花。
First, a floral offering for the bride from the unmarried girls of the island.
当地庆祝婚礼的习俗
A local custom for celebrating weddings.
——继续。——音乐。
- Proceed. - Music.
看。你的胡子露出来了。
Watch it. Your beard is showing.
我们开始吧。
Here we go.
这些乡下人的模样不合我的口味。
These peasant shapes are not to my taste.
死亡Gruda !
Death to Gruda!
杀了他们!
Kill them!
左舷电池。火!
Port side battery. Fire!
不，我是说左边。离开了!
No, I mean left. Left!
不。正确的。不，留了一点。
No. Right. No, left a bit.
你怎么了?
What's the matter with you?
你不知道你要去哪里吗?
Don't you know where you're going?
火!
Fire!
我们去追那个女孩。
We're going after the girl.
让我们脱光吧。
Let's strip for action.
停止!
Halt!
我们要把她碎尸万段。男人你的大炮。
We'll cut her to pieces. Man your cannons.
来吧,现在。
Come on, now.
高爆炸药。快。
The high explosive. Quick.
——开始!-是，是，先生。
- Get underway! - Aye, aye, sir.
男人的绞盘!
Man the capstan!
让她下面。
Get her below.
不要浪费时间。狭缝的电缆!
Don't waste time. Slit the cable!
我们得提高高度。卸压舱物。
We've got to gain altitude. Unload the ballast.
来吧。摆脱某物
Come on. Get rid of something.
-这是什么?这是上天的愤怒!
- What is it? - It is the wrath of heaven!
它摧毁了堡垒!
It has destroyed the fortress!
我们的船和我们的人。我们正朝他们冲去。
Our ship and our lads. We're heading straight for them.
使它关闭。
Make it close.
但不要太近。
But not too close.
我们需要我们的船和我们的人去抓格鲁达。
We'll need our ship and our lads to catch Gruda.
他们要把我们炸飞!快逃命!
They're going to blow us up! Jump for your lives!
-是我们自己的船长!-我们知道你会来。
- It's our own skipper! - We knew you'd come.
让我们离开这艘船。
Get us off this ship.
-把绳子割断。-带我们离开这里!
- Cut the rope down. - Get us out of here!
把所有的帆布都带上，你们这些童话般的海蛇!
Pack out all canvas, you fairy-tale sea snakes!
去找他们!
Go get 'em!
移动它们!
Move them!
动!
Move!
我真的觉得他打算和我们开战。
I really think he plans to do battle with us.
瓦洛船长不仅失去了理智，还失去了心脏。
Captain Vallo's lost his head as well as his heart.
拉臂。
Haul that jib.
修剪顶端的绞架。
Trim those top gallows.
两个点右舷。
Two points starboard.
不要开火，以备舷侧攻击。
Hold your fire for a broadside.
我们要火吗?
Shall we fire?
有那个女孩在船上就不能开火。我们要让她寄宿。
There'll be no firing with the girl on the ship. We're going to board her.
你们都到甲板下面去。
Below decks, the lot of you.
在双。
On the double.
未来,波纹管先生?
Coming, Mr. Bellows?
那些傻瓜要和我们交换武器。
The fools are going to trade broadsides with us.
在你去。
In you go.
没有人掌舵，我们无法靠边。
With nobody at the wheel to steer, we'll not get alongside.
现在担心已经来不及了。我们只能碰碰运气了。
Too late to worry about it. We'll have to take our chances.
你们的愿望。我们就去。
As ye wish. We'll go.
我诚挚的歉意。
My humble apologies.
但如果我不能像海盗一样活着，我也会像海盗一样死去。
But if I can't live like a pirate, I'll die like one.
我会站在船边，把船开过来。
I'll stand by the wheel and bring her alongside.
队长!给他们点颜色看看!
Skipper! Do them the dirty!
准备开火!
Stand by to fire!
开火!
Fire!
我们迷路了!女孩!
We're lost! Get the girl!
等等，教授!我们赢了!
Hold it, Professor! We've won!
扔掉那些东西。
Get rid of that stuff.